# **Shujin Wang**

GIS/Cartography Student | Map Lover | Continuous Learner

Email | shujin.wang@wisc.edu Address | 5C 2924 Harvey St., Madison, WI 53705 Phone | +1 (608) 572-9993

# **SUMMARY**

Student with 4 years of experience in GIS. Skilled in spatial data collection and management, raster/vector geospatial data analysis, remote sensing applications, web mapping, visual storytelling and cartographic presentation. Having strong background in physical and environmental geography while having knowledge of public health, urbanization, marketing geography and municipal mapping.

## **EDUCATION BACKGROUND**

September 2019 - August 2020 (estimated) | Madison, WI

## University of Wisconsin-Madison | Accelerated Master's in Cartography and GIS

- > Create paper-based and web-based reference and thematic maps
- > Take course in advanced spatial statistics

September 2018 - June 2019 | Lindsay, ON, Canada

#### Fleming College | Ontario Graduate Certificate in GIS - Cartographic Specialist

- > Conducted spatial analysis and environmental modelling
- > Designed websites in HTML/CSS and web maps on multiple platforms
- > Processed and interpreted remote sensing images in PCI Geomatica
- > Performed land surveying and manage spatial data in Access
- > Produced thematic maps and infographics that follow cartographic principles
- > Created and designed basemap and icon set specially for web mapping

September 2014 - June 2018 | Toronto, ON, Canada

## University of Toronto | H.BSc in Physical and Environmental Geography, GIS Minor

- > Took courses in watershed hydroecology, fluvial geomorphology, soil science, biosphere-atmosphere interactions, sustainable use of natural resource, etc.
- > Performed digitizing and georeferencing
- > Created an interactive map of world cuisine in Toronto using Mapbox APIs
- > Performed spatial analysis and hydrological mapping using ArcPy
- > Conduct network analysis and spatial statistics for topics in public health

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

September 2019 – January 2020 | Madison, WI

# State Cartographer's Office | GISPP Intern

- > Create web narrative map for flood events in Ashland, WI using a JavaScript library for story map and basic HTML/CSS skills
- > Design and create customized terrain basemap tiles in ArcMap

January 2019 - June 2019 | Port Hope, ON, Canada

#### Municipality of Port Hope | GIS Analyst Intern

- > Organized spatial dataset for municipal wastewater system
- > Built hydrological model and web application to locate pipeline inefficiencies
- > Created cartographic products to show analysis result

## **VOLUNTEER & ACTIVITIES**

May 2018 | Guizhou, China

# Zhaihao Middle School | Volunteer Rural Teacher

- > Designed and taught courses for grade 7 and grade 8 geography
- > Communicated with students and their parents
- > Designed and organized extracurricular activities such as poster making

# RESEARCH & PROJECTS

- 1. Natural Hazard Risk Assessment for City of Houston, Texas, USA
  - > Built a model to assess the impact of hurricane on Houston, considering both human and natural factors
  - Measured the accessibility to emergency facilities using network analysis and evaluated the overall vulnerability index using weighted overlay
- 2. Impacts of Climate on Ecosystem Production and Transpiration
  - > Performed simulations with BEPS-TerrainLab Model
- 3. Riffle-Pool Sequence Morphology and the Impact of Channel Geomorphic Characteristics on Riffle-Pool Spacing in Kettleby Creek, Ontario
  - > Collected and mapped field data

## **SKILLS & HIGHLIGHTS**

GIS & Spatial Analysis

- > ArcGIS Desktop (ArcMap, ArcScene, ArcCatalog)
- > ArcGIS Pro
- > GeoDa, Crime Stat
- > Collector, Survey 123
- > PCI Geomatics

# Cartography & Drafting

- > Adobe Illustrator, MAPublisher
- > Adobe Photoshop
- > AutoCAD

# Web & Programming

- > Geocortex Essentials
- > ArcGIS Online, ArcGIS Server
- > Python (ArcPy, GDAL, ORG)
- > HTML/CSS
- > JavaScript for Mapbox APIs
- > Google Map APIs
- > SQL, SQL Server
- > Mapbox Studio

## Others

> Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Visio, Access, PowerPoint)

## Languages

- > Academic English
- > Chinese Mandarin (Native)